<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vaccination on YKM&#39;s Corner on the Web</title>
    <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/categories/vaccination/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vaccination on YKM&#39;s Corner on the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://yeokhengmeng.com/categories/vaccination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Dos and Don&#39;ts when trying to convince the unvaccinated</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2021/08/my-dos-and-donts-when-trying-to-convince-the-unvaccinated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2021/08/my-dos-and-donts-when-trying-to-convince-the-unvaccinated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Singapore&amp;rsquo;s COVID vaccination programme has been doing very well by worldwide standards at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moh.gov.sg/news-highlights/details/update-on-local-covid-19-situation-and-vaccination-progress-(16-august-2021)&#34;&gt;76% who received 2 doses&lt;/a&gt; since 16 Aug 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Forgive me for stating the obvious but I&amp;rsquo;m part of this majority group. I&amp;rsquo;m considered fully vaccinated as I&amp;rsquo;m more than 2 weeks past my second shot. Still, I don&amp;rsquo;t subscribe to the mentality that that should be the end of the story for me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout my interactions in daily life, I have met some people for some reason or another, have not chosen to get vaccinated. In absolute numbers, the size of this group is still significant even after taking away children under 12 who cannot be vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;anti-vaxer&amp;rdquo; has been thrown around a lot to describe this group of people but I believe the situation is never as simple as a label.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I chose to listen to them to find out what are some of their concerns and if possible see if I can persuade them to change their mind. In those conversations, I have to admit I gained a lot as well, hence I decided to write this post to share my consolidated learnings and my opinions on what best to do and not do when trying to convince them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
