<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>retrocomputing on YKM&#39;s Corner on the Web</title>
    <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/categories/retrocomputing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in retrocomputing on YKM&#39;s Corner on the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yeokhengmeng.com/categories/retrocomputing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teardown &amp; review of a new 386 system: Hand386</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2023/06/teardown-and-review-of-hand386/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2023/06/teardown-and-review-of-hand386/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new 386-based palmtop recently appeared on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vi.aliexpress.com/item/1005005542582463.html&#34;&gt;Aliexpress&lt;/a&gt; and was covered by sites like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tomshardware.com/news/hand-386-handheld&#34;&gt;Tom&amp;rsquo;s Hardware&lt;/a&gt;. My curiosity was stoked and I quickly snapped one up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a DOS ChatGPT client in 2023</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2023/03/building-a-dos-chatgpt-client-in-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2023/03/building-a-dos-chatgpt-client-in-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the recent attention on ChatGPT and &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com/blog/introducing-chatgpt-and-whisper-apis&#34;&gt;OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s release of their APIs&lt;/a&gt;, many developers have developed clients for modern platforms to talk to this super smart AI chatbot. However I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure almost nobody has written one for a vintage platform like MS-DOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This client now supports Hugging Face API and text to speech (TTS) capability. More info on TTS is found at the later part of this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a 486 retro PC</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2021/05/setting-up-a-486-retro-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2021/05/setting-up-a-486-retro-pc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first computer I used as a kid was a 486 PC back in 1995. My family upgraded past it and it was disposed of. However very recently, someone in the local tech community donated a 486 motherboard to me. This gave me an opportunity to relive some of my childhood!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of giving back to the online community that I have learned a lot from, I decided to write this blog post to share my setup and learnings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of a new-old motherboard NuXT v2.0</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2020/05/review-of-a-new-old-motherboard-nuxt-v2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2020/05/review-of-a-new-old-motherboard-nuxt-v2.0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased a new-old motherboard. It&amp;rsquo;s a motherboard released in 2020 but not the usual you would expect of the latest motherboard released this year that support the latest CPUs and connectivity options. This motherboard supports a CPU first released in 1979 (Intel 8088) and comes with historic connectivity options like serial and parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first heard about the earlier iteration of this board the NuXT v1.2 version from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pwzHurzTNTY&#34;&gt;retrocomputing Youtuber LGR&lt;/a&gt;, I was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the latest new and improved NuXTv2.0 released recently, I decided to get one too as I needed a platform to go into coding for DOS to support the earliest IBM PCs. You can purchase this board &lt;a href=&#34;https://monotech.fwscart.com/NuXT_v20_-_MicroATX_Turbo_XT_-_10MHz_832K_XT-IDE_Multi-IO_SVGA/p6083514_19777986.aspx&#34;&gt;here at Monotech PCs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;images/nuxt-full-closeup.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/nuxt-full-closeup.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motherboard as installed in a modern micro-ATX case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;images/nuxt-external.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/nuxt-external.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an IDE hard disk caddy, Gotek Floppy Emulator with HxC firmware and a venerable 1.44MB Floppy Drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EFFsHvKXUKU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

The bootup process. Notice the bootup sound which is the PC Speaker playing the Intel chime. What attention to detail!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part, the motherboard schematic is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/monotech/NuXTv2&#34;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt; since it is itself based on other open-source projects. How many motherboards released today can claim that???&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a new Win 3.1 app in 2019 Part 1: Slack client</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2019/12/building-a-new-win-3-1-app-in-2019-part-1-slack-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2019/12/building-a-new-win-3-1-app-in-2019-part-1-slack-client/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October 2019, my company SP Digital held an internal hackathon. My colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/subhransu&#34;&gt;Subhransu&lt;/a&gt; and I worked on a whacky idea of writing a brand-new &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_3.1x&#34;&gt;Windows 3.1&lt;/a&gt; app which was an OS released almost 30 years ago. The idea we chose was a Slack client. After all, Slack clients exist for most platforms but I&amp;rsquo;m certain one does not exist for Windows 3.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months later in Dec 2019, I would join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://supersillyhackathon.sg/&#34;&gt;Super Silly Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; for the second time with fellow retrocomputing enthusiast &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chenhuijing.com/&#34;&gt;Hui Jing&lt;/a&gt;. We would develop a small game for Win 3.1 with great help from the knowledge gained from this first project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Part 1, I shall detail the learnings and process for how a new old app can be created with the aid of modern tools and hindsight of old technologies. And perhaps what lessons can it offer us today. This blog post is a few months late as I needed time to clean up the code and write the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to checkout out Part 2 of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chenhuijing.com/blog/building-a-win31-app-in-2019/&#34;&gt;game app with Hui Jing&lt;/a&gt; too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-app&#34;&gt;The App&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/wfwslack-shot.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/wfwslack-shot.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/wfwslack-both-1024x408.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/wfwslack-both-1024x408.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I use the IBM Model M keyboard that is older than me?</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2018/07/why-i-use-the-ibm-model-m-keyboard-that-is-older-than-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2018/07/why-i-use-the-ibm-model-m-keyboard-that-is-older-than-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last primary keyboard I&amp;rsquo;ll use in my life might be the IBM Model M. It&amp;rsquo;ll probably last me the decades to the day that keyboards should become obsolete. - Kheng Meng, 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just had to start my blog post with that self quote ^^^ but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty confident it&amp;rsquo;ll hold true for me. I have owned several keyboards so far and I have to say the Model M with its legendary buckling-spring switch is the one that fits my needs perfectly for the foreseeable future. This blog post was indeed also written on the Model M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/keyb-all.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/keyb-all-1024x380.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the mechanical keyboards I have owned so far&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Science Project: &#34;Make the 486 Great Again!&#34; - Modern Linux in an ancient PC</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2018/01/make-the-486-great-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2018/01/make-the-486-great-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the oldest x86 processor that is still supported by a modern Linux kernel in present time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked the above quiz question during the &lt;a href=&#34;https://geekcamp.sg/&#34;&gt;Geekcamp&lt;/a&gt; tech conference in Nov 2017 during &lt;a href=&#34;http://yeokhengmeng.com/2017/11/my-first-conference-emcee-experience/&#34;&gt;my emcee role&lt;/a&gt;. The theoretical answer as you can glean from the title of this post is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intel_80486&#34;&gt;486&lt;/a&gt; which was first released in 1989. I determined that fact from this article where &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcworld.com/article/2020196/linux-3-8-will-drop-support-for-intel-386-chips.html&#34;&gt;support for the 386 was dropped in Dec 2012&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get you interested, here is the result of my effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/gentoo-486-capabilities.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/gentoo-486-capabilities-939x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Science Project: Bringing the Covox Speech Thing to 2017</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2017/01/a-science-project-bringing-the-covox-speech-thing-to-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2017/01/a-science-project-bringing-the-covox-speech-thing-to-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Covox_Speech_Thing&#34;&gt;Covox Speech Thing&lt;/a&gt; (CST) was a sound card released in 1986 by Covox, Inc to enable computers with parallel ports to have sound capability. Unlike modern machines, proper sound support was not a given on computers in that era and the Soundblaster by Creative has yet to be released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you will see later, the design is rather simple so I decided to revisit this old piece of hardware and see if it is possible to get it working on modern systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/covox-music-player.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/covox-music-player-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My remake of the Covox Speech Thing with a self-wrote media player software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jAaXj0RK7V8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video of everything in action&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Science Project: Windows for Workgroups 3.11 on vintage and modern hardware in 2016</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2016/09/windows-for-workgroups-3-11-on-vintage-and-modern-hardware-in-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2016/09/windows-for-workgroups-3-11-on-vintage-and-modern-hardware-in-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(This is a long 5600+ words post, I recommend reading this from a tablet or computer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows for Workgroups 3.11 (WFW3.11) was an operating system (OS) released by Microsoft in August 1993 and ended support in December 2001. It is part of a series of OSes released by Microsoft at that time so it is common for people to refer to it as part of Windows 3.1x (Win3.1). The specific history behind its name and version number and be found on its &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Windows_3.1x&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt;. Here is a brief list of first-impressions I have if I were to describe this OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First Windows OS to have practical (installable) networking capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last one to not have a Start Menu and legacy interface before Windows 95&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last OS to require DOS as an initial install&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last 16-bit OS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/wfw-first.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/wfw-first-1024x739.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wfw-first&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a teaser screenshot showing that I managed to get WFW3.11 installed on a &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; 2009 Thinkpad T400 with networking capabilities. Recognise some familiar applications there?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Windows XP on a modern unsupported (Haswell) system in 2016</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2016/04/installing-windows-xp-on-a-modern-unsupported-haswell-system-in-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2016/04/installing-windows-xp-on-a-modern-unsupported-haswell-system-in-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(This is a long ~2900 words post, I recommend reading this from a tablet or computer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows XP is the second-longest supported operating system (OS) in Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s history. Support by Microsoft finally &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/WindowsForBusiness/end-of-xp-support&#34;&gt;ended on 8 April 2014&lt;/a&gt; after a record-setting 12.5 years.  The number one rank is technically* held by Windows 1.0 at 16 years from 1985 to 2001.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*I say &amp;ldquo;technically&amp;rdquo; as that was when Microsoft finally declared Win 1.0 obsolete but I doubt Microsoft was updating Win 1.0 during its final years. This was unlike WinXP which was updated up to its final moments and even had an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cnet.com/news/microsoft-fixes-big-ie-bug-on-windows-xp-even/&#34;&gt;emergency patch&lt;/a&gt; after its support ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/windows-xp-lasted-longer-world-wars-ii-combined/&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; here also puts XP&amp;rsquo;s length of support in perspective with other Microsoft OSes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released in October 2001, it is almost 15 years old today.  I was only 11 years old when this OS was released so you can imagine I pretty much spent much of my teen years using XP machines other than Red Hat Linux of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its age, XP continues to live on in embedded systems like ATMs, factory and medical machines where replacement costs and re-certification (timelines) makes them infeasible to be replaced in the near future. An extreme example is how the 23-year-old &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zdnet.com/article/a-23-year-old-windows-3-1-system-failure-crashed-paris-airport/&#34;&gt;Windows 3.1 which crashed is still used in a French airport&lt;/a&gt; as of late last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The problem&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work in a startup called Algoaccess where we deal with medical devices specifically optician-related ones. Without going into too much detail, let&amp;rsquo;s just say we occasionally have to handle such older systems and test to make sure our product can work with them. This means we actually need a Windows XP installation for testing purposes. No, virtual machines like VirtualBox or VMWare will not cut it, we need a native installation for realistic testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My company could easily procure a machine of an older era with full Windows XP drivers. There are guides like &lt;a href=&#34;http://multimedia.cx/eggs/running-windows-xp-in-2016/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; where people have used an older system to install WinXP in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where is the fun in that? I saw this as an opportunity to determine if it is really possible to install WinXP on a much newer system.  It was also a good way to relive a bit of my childhood that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thoughts? It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be that hard right? I know drivers could be an issue but it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a show-stopper? Turns out things are not so easy to put WinXP on modern hardware.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
