<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>repair-kopitiam on YKM&#39;s Corner on the Web</title>
    <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/categories/repair-kopitiam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in repair-kopitiam on YKM&#39;s Corner on the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://yeokhengmeng.com/categories/repair-kopitiam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Repair Kopitiam specialty electrical tools (Part 2): Short Circuit Limiter</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2017/07/repair-kopitiam-specialty-electrical-tools-part-2-short-circuit-limiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2017/07/repair-kopitiam-specialty-electrical-tools-part-2-short-circuit-limiter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have not read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://yeokhengmeng.com/2016/05/repair-kopitiam-speciality-electrical-tools/&#34;&gt;previous post (Part 1)&lt;/a&gt; on this subject, I encourage you but it is not mandatory to do so before reading this post. I&amp;rsquo;ll still go through the fundamentals in this post. If you just want to see the raw technical details, the schematic and code of this project have been &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yeokm1/repair-kopitiam-training-and-equipment/tree/master/short-circuit-limiter&#34;&gt;open-sourced here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;post-objective&#34;&gt;Post Objective&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To show why did I build this and how it works plus the issues faced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/rk-equip2-scl-prod-front.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/rk-equip2-scl-prod-front-1024x701.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clean case hides the complexity within.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repair Kopitiam specialty electrical tools</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2016/05/repair-kopitiam-speciality-electrical-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2016/05/repair-kopitiam-speciality-electrical-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m part of this voluntary social initiative called &lt;a href=&#34;http://repairkopitiam.sg/&#34;&gt;Repair Kopitiam&lt;/a&gt; (RK) started by the social enterprise &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sl2square.org/&#34;&gt;Sustainable Living Lab&lt;/a&gt;. On a monthly basis, we teach Singapore residents how to repair their household electrical appliances, fabrics and furniture. Our volunteers are called repair coaches. This initiative is similar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Repair_Caf%C3%A9&#34;&gt;Repair Cafes&lt;/a&gt; which originated in Europe. My area of speciality is of course in the electrical appliance department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is however not about the intricate details of volunteering, it will be about the special electrical tools I have developed in the course of my volunteering in response to certain unique issues faced by the RK team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A literally high-level view of the tools I developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/rk-equip-equipment-overview-small.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/rk-equip-equipment-overview-small-1024x802.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rk-equip-equipment-overview-small&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulau Semakau trip</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2016/02/pulau-semakau-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2016/02/pulau-semakau-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not everyday that one is like a tourist in our own country. I went on a trip with my fellow &lt;a href=&#34;http://repairkopitiam.sg/&#34;&gt;Repair Kopitiam&lt;/a&gt; coaches and others for a practically once-in-a-lifetime experience to Pulau Semakau, an island located 8km south of the mainland. It is affectionately known as a landfill island, where our incinerated trash gets sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who would have known the cleanest public area in Singapore is the landfill itself!!! What a revelation! Our guide boasted that there are no cockroaches and other pests cos there is nothing left for them to consume. I also learned that the landfill island is actually a reclaimed combination of the original Pulau Semakau and Pulau Sakeng.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costing some SG$600 million to reclaim and build in 1990s dollars, it is probably one of the most expensive projects undertaken by the government that are outside of the public eye and concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;images/admin-building.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/admin-building.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;admin-building&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A view of the outside of the main administration building and the bus that will take us on the tour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
