<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hackathon on YKM&#39;s Corner on the Web</title>
    <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/categories/hackathon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hackathon on YKM&#39;s Corner on the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://yeokhengmeng.com/categories/hackathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NUS Hack&amp;Roll 2015 AAR</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2015/01/nus-hackroll-2015-aar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2015/01/nus-hackroll-2015-aar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the third Hack&amp;amp;Roll hackathon I have joined and my very last one for this hackathon and as an NUS student.  Can check out my first two &lt;a href=&#34;http://yeokhengmeng.com/2014/01/what-i-did-nus-hackroll-2014/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://yeokhengmeng.com/2013/02/my-experience-nus-hackroll-2013/&#34; title=&#34;here&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Didn&amp;rsquo;t win anything but not that we were expecting any, it is the stuff we learned that were most important.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So presenting to you the Raspilizer! Done by myself and my friends Kai Yao (KY) and Yong Quan (YQ), two of my technical go-to buddies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;rasplizer&#34; src=&#34;http://yeokhengmeng.com/2015/01/nus-hackroll-2015-aar/images/rasplizer.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An independent device that does dynamic audio compression in &amp;ldquo;almost&amp;rdquo; realtime. Just feed in audio via the 3.5mm input jack and connect your speakers/headphones to the output jack!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>code::XtremeApps:: 2014 Hackathon AAR</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2014/07/codextremeapps-2014-hackathon-aar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2014/07/codextremeapps-2014-hackathon-aar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the third hackathon I have joined and the first that involves hardware. Although my team was not selected to go for the next round of judging, I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have learned alot during this IDA-organised XtremeApps hackathon held at SMU.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My team comprising Muneer, Sathish and myself brainstormed on the first day for ideas based on the themes given. We decided to build something to help the visually-impaired identify buses when they are at the bus stop. We came up with this idea when we remembered that the visually-impaired had to stop every bus to ask the driver for the number if no one was around or constantly question the people around him. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be a good thing if we could automate this tiresome process?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I did in NUS Hack&amp;Roll 2014</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2014/01/what-i-did-in-nus-hackroll-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2014/01/what-i-did-in-nus-hackroll-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NUS Hackers tried to encourage participants to write a blog post or on social media about their experiences in the HacknRoll 2014, so here it is.  Nah, I would have written this anyway without their encouragement. But after they read what I wrote, I wonder if they would still share it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So this hackathon which was on 25-26 Jan was the second one I had attended. You can read up about my first one &lt;a href=&#34;http://yeokhengmeng.com/2013/02/my-experience-nus-hackroll-2013&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Although this time, instead of being “drafted” into a team by an acquaintance, I was the one who asked a few people if they willing to join my team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea we agreed to work on was the iOS version of the SoC print app. I first started on the Android version of that app nearly one year ago. From that point up to now, several  SoC friends have asked me for an iOS version. As I did not have a Mac, an iOS device or knowledge of Objective-C, there was no way for me to pick up iOS programming much less write an iOS app. Fast forward 10 months later, I’m in CS3217 with basic knowledge of Objective-C, have a Mac and a CS3217 rental iPad,  I have the tools to do so now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have several peeves with the way this hackathon was organised compared to last year but I shall leave that to the later part of this article. &lt;img alt=&#34;HacknRoll 2014 my team&#34; src=&#34;http://yeokhengmeng.com/2014/01/what-i-did-in-nus-hackroll-2014/images/HacknRoll-2014-my-team.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So here is my team in planning/discussion/problem solving  when we were “shot”. From left, Kaiyao, myself and Yong Quan. Both of them were also the beta testers for my Android app.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PRGcK7gzbnM?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&#xA;      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our project video. Narration was done by Yong Quan. (Try to view in HD if possible)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My experience in NUS Hack&amp;Roll 2013</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2013/02/my-experience-in-nus-hackroll-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2013/02/my-experience-in-nus-hackroll-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I confess I signed up for this weekend event at the last minute. One of the team members who was an acquaintance of mine said they needed one more member so I joined. I can say, I left this 24hour hackathon today with no regrets other than the proverbial, I could have done that better in hindsight attitude. This was my first hackathon and most definitely won&amp;rsquo;t be my last.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sitting down with your team coding through the day and night then day again for only a single goal while surviving on a steady supply of snacks, soft drinks and fast food is an unforgettable experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Hacknroll 2013 team pic&#34; src=&#34;http://yeokhengmeng.com/2013/02/my-experience-in-nus-hackroll-2013/images/hacknroll2013teampic.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My team, which I barely knew before the event but nonetheless worked reasonably well together in the end.&#xA; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
