<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quiz on YKM&#39;s Corner on the Web</title>
    <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/categories/quiz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quiz on YKM&#39;s Corner on the Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://yeokhengmeng.com/categories/quiz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Singapore quiz in iOSConfSG 2020</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2020/01/singapore-quiz-in-iosconfsg-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2020/01/singapore-quiz-in-iosconfsg-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During &lt;a href=&#34;https://2020.iosconf.sg/&#34;&gt;iOSConfSG 2020&lt;/a&gt;, I was asked by the organising team to give a Singapore quiz as part of my emcee role.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was given sufficient notice period to come up with these 16 questions but I felt I could do better if I didn&amp;rsquo;t wait till the last minute. Nevertheless, I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll will enjoy them. Quite a few people told me they liked it so I think it went okay but there were some controversies. So hence this blog post with the sources provided as well as my thoughts behind the possible answers behind each question.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s start with the questions and possible answers first! Once you are done, scroll further down for the solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trivia Questions asked during GeekcampSG 2019</title>
      <link>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2019/10/trivia-questions-asked-during-geekcampsg-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://yeokhengmeng.com/2019/10/trivia-questions-asked-during-geekcampsg-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was the emcee in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/events/384878335732606/&#34;&gt;GeekcampSG 2019.&lt;/a&gt; I asked a total of 66 trivia questions in the effort and excuse to give out leftover plushies from the previous Geekcamp 2018+.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yeokhengmeng.com/2019/10/trivia-questions-asked-during-geekcampsg-2019/images/geekcampsg2019-pluhies.jpg.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://yeokhengmeng.com/2019/10/trivia-questions-asked-during-geekcampsg-2019/images/geekcampsg2019-pluhies.jpg-1024x389.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These questions spanned topics from Singapore, Science, Fiction, Computing, Retro-tech and miscellaneous general knowledge. Topics I feel would appeal to a stereotypical geek audience and someone like myself. Try to see how many you can answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trust me, the collating of these questions and researching their answers took over a period of several years to prepare for such a day. It was fun to finally see the fruits of my labour. Coming up with questions that can&amp;rsquo;t be too easy that everyone knows the answer or too hard that no one knows is difficult. Fortunately for me, at least 3/4 of the questions could be answered correctly by at least one person.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
